Guide to the Israel Cohen Papers Relating to His Book Collection
Israel Cohen Papers relating to his book collection,
- Serials, Series 20.; 12 folders
  - Serials: Rashe perakim le-hasbarah, no. 35. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Rashe perakim le-hasbarah: Levanon. No. 35 in a series of factsheets published by the Israel Defense Forces. Ca. 1955.
  - Serials: Reshafim: ba-derekh el ha-geulah ha-shelemah. 1957. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Newsletter on topics pertaining to Orthodox Judaism and politics. Jerusalem: no. 10, 1957.
  - Serials: ha-Tsefirah. 1862. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    ha-Tsefirah: mikhtav iti mashmia hadashot [weekly newspaper in Hebrew and Yiddish]. No. 1, Warsaw: 1862.
- Tear sheets, Series 21.; 3 folders
  Tear sheets from monographs and scholarly journals, some attached to title page photocopies of the books in which they were found.
  - Tear sheets (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Tear sheets from monographs and journal articles, some attached to title page photocopies of the books in which they were found.
  - Tear sheets (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Tear sheets (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Tourist Pamphlets and Visitor Guides, Series 22.; 2 folders
  - Travel pamphlets/Visitor guides (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Six tourist pamphlets; five from Israel, one from Denmark.
  - Travel pamphlets/Visitor guides (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Folder containing information on the city of Rishon Le Zion, Israel. 1980s.
- Writings by Others, Series 23.; 5 folders
  Unpublished materials mainly not written by Israel Cohen.
  - Essays, Subseries 1.; 3 folders
    - Writing by others: Essays (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Essays and commentary by writers other than Israel Cohen.
    - Writing by others: Essays (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Writing by others: Essays (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Poems, Subseries 2.; 1 folder
    - Writing by others: Poems (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Handwritten and typed poems by writers other than Israel Cohen.
  - Songs, Subseries 3.; 1 folder
    - Writing by others: Songs (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Handwritten and typed songs by writers other than Israel Cohen.
  - Speeches, Subseries 4.; 4 folders
    Photocopies of title page inscriptions and autographs, alphabetized according to author or editor's last name.
    - Writing by others: Speeches (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Speeches by writers other than Israel Cohen.
- Photocopies of Inscriptions, Series 24.; 4 folders
  - Photocopied inscriptions: A-F (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Photocopies of title page inscriptions, alphabetized according to author or editor's last name.
  - Photocopied inscriptions: G-O (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Photocopied inscriptions: P-S (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Photocopied inscriptions: T-Z (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Political Campaign Materials, Series 25.; 1 folder
  Pamphlets from various political campaigns. Of special interest: six-page newsprint pamphlet with biographical information on 120 Mapai members [Workers' Party of Erets Yisrael] running for election to the Knesset, including David Ben Gurion and Moshe Dayan, ca. 1958.
  - Political campaign materials (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Pamphlets for various political campaigns. Of special interest: six-page pamplet with biographical information on the 120 Mapai members [Workers' Party of Erets Yisrael], including David Ben Gurion and Moshe Dayan, ca. 1958.